CHRISTIAAN SIMMONS

Plymouth, MN 55447

Phone: 773-290-4240 | Email: christiaan.simmons@live.com | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/christiaan-simmons-61116323 |

Github: https://github.com/montechristiaan |

Portfolio: https://montechristiaan.github.io/UpdatedPortfolio/index.html

SUMMARY

User-focused Web Developer who enjoys taking on challenges and deadlines in high-stress situations. Adapted a successful career in live television production to provide "big picture" ideas for how users experience websites and apps.

A veteran producer of live television in markets like Las Vegas, Chicago, and the Twin Cities. Covered every kind of breaking situation in real time with the ability to multi-task and problem-solve on the fly. Saw projects through from start to finish on a daily basis, while successfully collaborating with teams and delegating responsibilities.

A passion for media on the front line of developing and deepening the user experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript, SQL, node.js

Skills: APIs, Database management, AP style, Journalism

EDUCATION

Full Stack Coding Certificate: University of Minnesota Twin Cities, St. Paul, MN A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, node.js, SQL Databases, Mongo, Express, and React.

Bachelor of the Arts: English/Music: Augsburg University, Minneapolis, MN BA with a major in English Literature and a minor in Music Theory.

PROJECTS

Birthday Tracker | github.com/pbrayer/Project1 | pbrayer.github.io/Project1

- The Birthday Tracker app allows users to track as many birthdays as they wish, regardless of where users sign in, along with sending reminders as the big day approaches, and suggestions for gift ideas based on the interests of friends/loved ones.
- Lead contributor to overall front-end design, using html and css to interact with the javascript for functionality and to make a clean, useable website.
- HTML, CSS, Javascript, AJAX, Firebase, APIs.

TrashTaggers | github.com/petr0n/TrashTaggers | trashtaggers.herokuapp.com

 TrashTaggers allows the user to create, search, or join a list of cleanup groups from whichever area they choose. The app uses Google authentication for sign-up and MySQL and JAWSdb to store information.

- Lead designer on front-end, creating look and functionality from scratch so that back-end collaborators could easily identify what was needed.
- HTML, CSS, Javascript, AJAX, MySQL, JAWSdb, heroku, APIs, node.js, sequelize, mocha, chai, express, express-handlebars.

EXPERIENCE

Supervising Producer: KARE11 Sunrise Morning Newscast KARE11-TV

2012 - 2017

Golden Valley, MN

Demonstrated technical knowledge and experience in building dynamic newscasts in an agile environment. Used creative and effective problem-solving to meet production challenges. Resolved critical issues in live newscasts or on the web. Wrote for the web in AP style and produced original video elements for online users.

Producer: Morning, Midday, Evening, & Weekend Newscasts KSTP-TV

2008 – 2012

St. Paul, MN

Progressively improved and iterated systems and capabilities of newscast rundowns to meet longer-term roadmap objectives. Enabled marketing team to create compelling narratives to help viewers understand station's unique offering. Understood and measured appropriate actions based on station analysis to gain insights about station performance & production.

Producer: "Fox News in the Morning with Tamron Hall" WFLD-TV

2003 – 2007

Chicago, IL

Coded, tested, debugged, documented, and maintained production rundowns. Helped plan and roadmap new features and functionality for live newscast and online users. Owned all components of newscast and directed the work of other team members. Assisted in designing segments to improve the viewer or user experience.

Producer/Editor: Morning Weekday & Weekend Newscasts KVBC-TV

2001 – 2003

Las Vegas, NV

Worked in rapid production environment where the ability to pivot is a must. Designed, planned, and implemented newscasts while building off of and making improvements to existing production. Interpreted ratings analysis to extract relevant data to improve viewership. Provided clear and consistent communication around solutions and time estimates to production team members and managers. Collaborated with promotions team to develop new features.